{
    "id": "8435763cad684712984c7e51dbd05ade",
    "title": "Simple, Complex vs. Compound",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "In spite of his hard work, he could not score good marks.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "899d70af551e4954853a9158036eb20a"
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as we heard the gunshots, we rushed indoors.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "971d024cf61a44fa8a8e696801df1a7c"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I opened the door, the cat jumped out.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9b605ab2a1554743b0dd8f24214a8980"
        },
        {
            "question": "His remarks angered me but I said nothing.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "52055d4e343241d28adff8843e361689"
        },
        {
            "question": "Though it was a holiday, I went to work as usual.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fc744e1caf0c40d2b8c0d93ad42681c9"
        },
        {
            "question": "If it rains, I will open the umbrella.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cda56dbb40bd483aa6c81e1220170643"
        },
        {
            "question": "She passed the test because of her hard work.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f61b8305bd7347e4a0b5e8883a4bc4ec"
        },
        {
            "question": "He failed despite his hard work.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "df2f4967baf2440b9ba505aa28c53624"
        },
        {
            "question": "It has been several months since we last met.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c4c9d40933de4b6ebdaecc3a91960f4f"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are in trouble because of your stupidity.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "377949bbfe35483cb2570a1d763e5aa6"
        },
        {
            "question": "She opened the book and started reading.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0ec6841de6aa4b95b06dc35b9328f10c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I turned around but I didnâ€™t see anyone.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "64151a2c254a427994f78c41152c508c"
        }
    ]
}